天啊
Oh, my god!
天啊  你在求婚
Oh, my god. You're proposing.
-好吧  你很惊讶  -我当然很惊讶
- Okay. You're surprised. - Of course I'm surprised.
我还以为你要和我分手
I thought you were breaking up with me.
分手还送戒指吗
By offering you a ring?
你就是...看起来好严肃
Well, you just-- you seemed so serious.
我当然严肃
Yeah, of course I'm serious.
-这是我做过的最严肃的事情  -太好了
- This is the most serious thing I've ever done. - Good.
这么说你同意了
So that's a "Yes"?
-不  等等  -不同意吗
- No, wait. - "No"?
-不不不  不是不同意  -那就是同意
- No, no, no, not--not "No." - So "Yes"?
-我  -不同意吗
- I... - Not "Yes"?
不  不是不同意
No. Not "Not yes."
我  我
I... I...
你明白这是怎么回事的吧
You do know how this works, right?
我得告诉你一件事
There's something that I have to tell you.
我被录用了
I got the job.
在特区
In D.C.?
卡塞尔  我爱你
Castle, I love you.
但这是我的机会
But this is my shot.
如果我不抓住机会  我会后悔一辈子
And if I don't do this, I'll always regret it.
如果这让你有所改变
Look, if this changes anything for you,
如果这改变了你的想法
if this changes the way that you feel--
凯特  我向你求婚不是为了把你留在这
Kate, I'm not proposing to you to keep you here
也不是害怕会失去你
or because I'm afraid I'm gonna lose you.
我求婚是因为我生命中不能没有你
I'm proposing because I can't imagine my life without you.
这意味着  如果遇到困难
If that means when things get difficult,
需要我们想办法解决
we have to figure them out,
那我愿意想办法
then I'm willing to figure them out,
假设你也愿意和我一起想办法
assuming you're willing to figure them out with me.
那样的话
Well, in that case,
理查德·埃德加·亚历山大·罗杰斯·卡塞尔
Richard Edgar Alexander Rodgers Castle,
我答应
yes.
我答应  我会嫁给你
Yes. I will marry you.
好大
It's big.
不  是你的手指太纤细了
No, you just have remarkably tiny fingers.
我们能解决这事的  对吧
We're gonna be able to make this work, right?
我们会没事的
We're gonna be great.
特区会很棒
D.C. is gonna be great.
我保证
I promise.
华盛顿特区
两个月后
小心
Look out!
联邦探员
Federal agent!
出来  双手抱头
Come out with your hands on your head!
把枪放到地上
Put your weapon on the ground.
-照办  -好  好  不必伤人
- Do it! - Okay. All right. Nobody needs to get hurt.
好吗
Okay?
我把枪放下  然后滑过去
I'm gonna put it down and I'm gonna slide it over.
好吗
Okay?
好了  给你
Okay, here it comes.
你还好吗  女士
You okay, ma'am?
我没事
I'm fine.
贝克特
Beckett!
贝克特探员
Agent beckett?
恭喜你
Congratulations.
因为你  车臣人拿到了我们的核弹发射密码
Because of you, the Chechens now have our nuclear launch codes.
干得好
Nice job.
该死
Damn it.
人质没有挣扎  难道你不觉得奇怪吗
You didn't find it odd that the hostage wasn't struggling?
她的头被一把枪顶着
She had a gun held to her head.
而她没有呼救  为什么
And she didn't cry out for help. Why?
因为她不想暴露口音  好吧
Because she didn't wanna give away her accent. Fine.
但是情报说特务是单独行动的
But the intel said that the operative worked alone.
这就是演习的意义
And that's the point of the exercise.
情报有时候有误
Intel is sometimes wrong.
你得用自己的判断和直觉
You have to use your judgment, your instinct,
因为吃枪子儿的人
because the analyst that's gathering that intel--
不是收集情报的分析员
he's not the one that's gonna be catching a bullet.
而是你  或者更糟糕  是我
That's gonna be you, or worse, me.
加油吧
Now step up your game.
麦考德
McCord!
人质巷没过吗
Hostage alley?
是啊
Yeah.
别难过  大家都搞砸过
Don't feel bad. Everyone screws that up.
-我本该发现的  -你瞧
- Should've seen it. - Hey, look,
在训练中丧命总比实战中死去要好  对吧
it's better to die in training than in the field, right?
-不死最好了  -是啊
- It's better not to die at all. - Yeah.
今晚我们几个同事要出去喝一杯
Listen, a few of us are grabbing a beer tonight.
你要来吗
You wanna join?
谢谢  亨德里克斯  我很想去
Thank you, Hendricks. I would love to,
但是最近案件那么多再加上训练
but with the caseload and the training,
我已经很久没享受过周末
I haven't had a weekend off in ages,
而且我已经有安排了
and I've actually got plans.
现在没有了
Not anymore.
司法部发来了七级重要事件
We just received a priority 7 from the A.G.
出事了
There's been an incident--
有个潜在的国家安全漏洞
A potential national security breach.
哟  浪子回来啦
Ah, the prodigal son returns.
西海岸的巡回签售如何
How was the West Coast book tour?
累死人了
It was exhausting.
11天去了12座城市
12 cities in 11 days.
手指都快签断了
I signed my fingers to the bone.
可怜的娃
You poor boy.
我去换衣服
I'm gonna go change.
让这家伙跟你说说近况吧
I'll let this guy fill you in on all the details.
他最擅长反问了
He's best with rhetorical questions.
-阿丽克西斯回来了吗  -是啊
- Is Alexis back? - Ah, yeah.
今早回来的
She came in this morning.
我以为她还在哥斯达黎加...
Oh, I thought she was in Costa Rica until--
下周才回来  惊喜
Next week. Surprise!
爸爸
Daddy?
快过来
Come here, you.
你的旅行怎么样
How was your trip?
太棒了
Amazing.
等下给你看我们的照片
Just wait till you see our pictures.
"我们的"照片
"Our" pictures?
阿尔  火柴放哪了
Hey, Al, where do you keep the matches?
我想点上这捆香
I wanna light these sage bundles.
又一个惊喜
Surprise again.
爸爸
Dad...
这位是派
Pi.
派  这是我爸
Pi, dad.
C先生
Hey, Mr. C.
很高兴见到你
Awesome to meet you.
派  是甜品的那个派吗
Pie. Like the dessert?
不加e  是希腊字母那个派
Without the "E." Like the greek letter.
但我个人认为
But personally, I feel
拼写什么的只会扼杀创造力
the whole spelling thing just stifles creativity.
拼写什么的
The "spelling thing"?
让我爸休息会儿吧  火柴在厨房里
Let's let my dad decompress. Matches are in the kitchen.
好的
Okay.
他  他不会住在这儿吧
He's-- he's not staying here?
会哦
Oh, he is.
不会睡在她房里吧
N-not in her room.
你去跟她说吧
Hey, you get to have that talk.
我要上课了  拜拜
I have a class. Ta-ta.
阿丽克西斯
Uh, Alexis?
能跟你谈谈吗
Could I talk to you a second?
给他一次机会吧  爸爸
Give him a chance, Dad.
我真的很喜欢他
I really like him.
他很聪明
And he's brilliant.
找到了
Found 'em!
晚点再谈
We'll talk about this later.
派要住这儿的话
Uh, make sure you put some, uh,
你记得给他拿点毯子铺在沙发上
blankets out on the couch for Pi if he's staying?
希望他住得舒服
Want him to be comfortable...
还要待在我眼皮底下
and visible.
你的航班没延误吧
Please tell me your flight is not delayed.
再见不到你我就要疯了
I don't think I can bear another minute not seeing you.
抱歉  我不在机场
I'm sorry. I'm not at the airport.
你不来了  是吧
You're not coming, are you?
上头派我处理一件紧急案子
I just got put on a priority case.
凯特  我们都六周没见面了
Kate, we haven't seen each other in six weeks.
相信我  我也不想的
Trust me. This was not my call.
我跟你一样难受
I'm just as upset as you are.
我明白...
No, I know. It's...
上次是我放你鸽子的
I'm the one who canceled last time.
贝克特  走吧
Beckett, let's go.
我得挂了
Look, I gotta go.
我会补偿你的  我保证
I will make this up to you, I promise.
好吧  就指着你的补偿了
All right, I'm gonna hold you to that.
好  我爱你
Okay. I love you.
我也爱你  再见
Love you, too. Bye.
再见
Bye.
笑什么笑
What are you smiling about?
能先把衣服脱了再向我开枪吗
Can you at least finish taking that off before you shoot me?
卡塞尔
Cas-Castle?
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我是保证过会尊重你的工作
I know I promised to respect your job,
但再见不到你我连一周都忍不了
but I couldn't go another week without seeing you.
你  你不该来的
You know, you--you shouldn't have come here.
那你要我走吗
So you want me to leave?
立刻
Oh, immediately.
天呐
Oh, God.
起床多久了
How long have you been up?
几个小时吧  有些作业要做
Couple of hours. I had some homework to do.
也许咱俩也该做些"作业"
Maybe we should do some homework, too.
我也想
Yeah, I would love to,
但我还要证明自己的能力
except I'm still proving myself.
我得比写报告的人
I got to know these reports
更了解这些报告
better than the people that wrote them.
这是你的案子吗
Is this your case?
-是的  -什么案子
- Yeah. - What's it about?
卡塞尔
Castle.
这是机密
It's classified.
你知道这么说只会让我更好奇吧
You do realize that only makes me more curious.
是大案子吗
So... is it big?
你知道我不能跟你谈论公事
You know I can't talk about it.
不代表我不能猜啊
Doesn't mean I can't guess.
肯定是大案子  都害你取消了我们的约会
It must be big. You had to cancel our weekend together.
肯定是本地的案子  因为你还在这里
Must be local, because you're still here.
我肯定能猜中
I bet I can figure this out.
不代表你应该这么做啊
Well, that doesn't mean that you should.
别这样  难道你不怀念我们共事的时光吗
Come on. Don't you miss working together?
怀念
Yes, I do.
要是让我帮忙的话  也许能快点处理完
So if I were to help you, maybe we could solve whatever...
这个案子
this is faster,
然后整个周末过二人世界
and then have the whole weekend to ourselves.
-你不想吗  -我想...
- Wouldn't you like that? - I would...
直到我因透露
Until I got arrested for disclosing
机密资料被捕
classified information.
别这样  谁会知道
Oh, come on. Who's gonna know?
他们真厉害
They're good.
我得走了  是我搭档来了
I gotta go. That's my partner.
抱歉  别  我自己捡
Sorry. No, no. I got it. I got it.
我没偷看
I'm not looking.
你什么时候回来
So what time will you be back?
你知道吗  我也不好说
I--you know what? I'm not quite sure.
我一知道就
I'll give you a call...
马上给你打电话
as soon as I find out.
快请进
Hey, come on in.
-你准备好了吗  -准备好了
- Are you ready? - Uh, yeah.
等我拿个包
I just gotta get my bag.
你未婚夫来看你了
Your fiance's visiting.
对
Yes.
他来了  而且他知道我们在工作
He is, except he knows that we're working.
卡塞尔  这是蕾切尔·麦考德
Uh, Castle, this is Rachel McCord.
她是我的新搭档
She's my new partner.
你就是那个新搭档
So you're the new partner.
对
Yep.
长官在等我们  走吧
Chief's waiting. Gotta go.
好
Yeah.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
祝你拯救世界
Have fun saving the...
愉快
world.
你忘了你的...
Oh, you forgot your, um...
好吧  现在...
All right. Now...
认真的吗
Seriously?
只有四个月了  我想做好准备
Only four months away. I wanna be ready.
这四个月一定非常漫长
It's gonna be a long four months.
我是埃斯波西托
Esposito.
西托  是我
'Sito! It's me.
卡塞尔  我把电话开免提
Castle? I'll put you on speaker.
你去哪儿了  兄弟
So where you been, bro?
你已经错过了三个光环游戏之夜
You've missed, like, three "Halo" Nights.
我跟你说了  我去巡回签售了
I told you, I was on a book tour.
是吗  你有没有告诉你的书迷
Yeah? Did you tell your book groupies
你已经订婚了
you're engaged now?
你在给娃娃包襁褓吧
You're swaddling that doll right now, aren't you?
听着  我们刚结束了一个案子
So listen, we just finished a case.
下班后来跟我们喝一杯吧
Come have a drink with us after work.
我很想去  但我正在忙自己的案子
Oh, I'd love to, but I'm working on a case of my own right now...
为了我的下一本书
For my next book.
所以你打电话
Oh, so you just called us
就是因为你需要专业技术顾问
'cause you need some expert technical consulting.
好吧  既然你主动提供了
Well, s-since you offered.
我在写一个关于
I'm writing a scene about someone
仅凭一张证据照片
trying to investigate a crime
调查案件的故事
using only one evidence photo--
一桩涉及国家安全的案件
A crime involving national security.
所以你的主角是个间谍
So your hero's a spy?
更像是个粗犷英俊的普通人
More like a... ruggedly handsome everyman.
不管怎样  照片里是个炸烂的变压器
Anyway, the photo is of a blown transformer,
所以我在网上随便找了张变压器的照片
so I pulled a random photo of a transformer off the internet,
上面有个序列号
and there's a serial number on the side.
我想试着看看
I'm trying to determine how much
我的主人公能通过这个号码发现多少
my character could figure out just from that number.
我在想我的主人公的
I'm wondering if my character's
警察朋友会不会有些资源
police buddies might have any... resources.
如果主人公的虚构警察朋友
Well, if your hero's fictional cop buddies
跟你真正的警察朋友一样的话
are anything like your real cop buddies,
他们还有真正的工作要做  所以
then they'd have real work to get back to, so...
-再见吧  -如果我们的主人公
- Bye-bye now. - What if...
能提供尼克斯队的场地票呢
our hero was offering Knicks floor seats?
那个序列号是多少
What's that serial number?
给
Here.
AP5739215
A-P-5-7-3-9-2-1-5.
找到了  AP代表爱兰歌娜电力
Here we go. The "AP" Stands for Allegra Power.
他们为北弗吉尼亚供电
They service Northern Virginia.
用那个号码能查到
And would it be possible to trace the location
变压器的位置吗
of that transformer using that number?
当然可以
Yeah, sure.
那个号码的变压器控制着
The transformer with that serial number controls
阿灵顿地区阿士顿高地
a 10-square block region
一块十平方英里的区域
of the Ashton heights neighborhood in Arlington.
谢了  伙计们  你们拯救了这个故事
Thanks, you guys. You saved the story.
伙计们  那个变压器
Guys, that exact transformer
事件: 爆炸破坏
保密: 联邦调查中
两天前被破坏了
was sabotaged two nights ago,
联邦探员正在调查
And the feds are investigating.
阿灵顿  不是贝克特的辖区吗
Arlington? Isn't that Beckett's backyard?
卡塞尔
Castle.
这是个真案子吧
Is this a real case?
其实  我  什么
Well, actually, I-- what?
隧道...  对...
Tunnel... Right...
等我...  有空...  打给你
call... later... when I...
拜...
B...
真机智
Smooth.
好吧
All right.
为什么要炸掉变压器呢
Why would someone blow up a transformer?
恐怖袭击
Terrorism.
不  那样新闻上会播的
No, that would have been in the news.
为了制造停电
To cause a blackout?
停电怎么会影响国家安全
How does a blackout affect national security?
停电暂时性地关闭了
The blackout momentarily shut down
赛博科技大楼的安保系统
the Cybertech building security system.
这个变压器供电
Now this particular facility
范围内有许多政府承包商
houses a number of government contractors.
其中一个是赛博科技
One of them is Cybertech Transnational.
有人进入了赛博科技的清洁室
Someone gained access to Cybertech's clean room
而且偷走了高度机密的硬件安全模块
and stole a highly classified hardware security module.
那个模块
This is that module
里面有军方卫星
that contains the encryption system
网络入口的加密系统
that serves as the gateway to the military satellite network.
拿走它的人
Whoever took it is capable of shutting
能够关掉整个卫星网络
that satellite network down completely.
这会导致大部分军方防御系统失效
Leaving a large portion of our military's defenses blind.
我们对窃贼了解多少
What do we know about our thieves?
不多  没有指纹  没有DNA的痕迹
Not much. There's no prints, no trace D.N.A.
但这是个很复杂的行动
But it was a highly complex operation.
所以我们认为罪犯
So we believe whoever pulled this off
一定经历过军事训练
had to have had military training
或者秘密行动
or stealth ops.
他们得炸掉变压器
They had to blow up the transformer,
停掉备用发电机
disable the backup generators,
然后从风井爬上去
then climb up this air shaft.
而且他们的速度得非常快
And they had to do it all extremely quickly,
因为即使停电让安保摄像头失效
because even though the blackout defeated the security cameras,
它们也会在五分钟后靠电池重启
they reset on battery power five minutes later.
这样的行动不可能在五分钟内完成
There's no way this operation took less than five minutes.
录像一定拍到了他们离开的画面
We must have video footage of them leaving.
不  长官  我们看了整个录像
No, Sir. We scrubbed the entire video.
什么都没有
There's nothing.
他们有可能还在楼里吗
Could they still be in the building?
不可能  除非已经死了
No, not if they're alive.
整个楼都用热成像扫描过  没发现有人
A thermal imaging sweep of the entire premises came up negative.
他们一定是找到了一条
They must have found a way out
能避开摄像头的出路
that didn't take them past the cameras.
没这样的路  长官
There isn't one, sir.
整个大楼外围都是百分之百监控的
The outside of the building has 100% coverage.
那楼底下呢
What about under the building?
底下
Under it?
常和敏感材料打交道的研究机构
A research facility dealing with sensitive materials
一定会有某种防洪设施
would need to have some sort of flood controls.
能把排水系统的图纸调出来吗
Can you pull up a map of the drainage system myriad?
-排水管就在大楼底下  -我们曾想到过
- Drainage tunnels go right under the building. - We thought of that.
我们排查过所有接入点
We checked all the access points,
包括排水口
including the drainage grids.
-它们都焊死了  -再查一遍
- They're all welded shut. - Check 'em again.
如果他们真是从地下走的
If they did use the tunnels,
他们不会跑太远
they wouldn't have wanted to travel too far.
所以他们会从附近一个
So they'd need to access the drainage system
夜晚无人使用的地方进入排水系统
from a nearby area-- one that's inactive at night.
就像...
Like...
这个高尔夫球场
this golf course.
谢谢
Thanks.
亨德里克斯从大楼打来电话
That was Hendricks from the building.
发现的确有人撬开了排水口
Turns out someone did pry open the drain grate,
出来后又重新焊上
then welded it on the way out.
你前途无量啊  贝克特
There's hope for you, Beckett.
至少我们知道我们找对路了
Well, at least we know we're on the right track.
打扰一下  联邦探员
Excuse me. Federal agents.
是关于昨晚断电的事吗
Uh, is this about the blackout the other night?
对  你怎么知道的
Yeah. How did you know that?
就像我跟另一个人说的那样
Well, like I told the other guy,
我昨晚不在  你们应该找沃金斯聊聊
I wasn't here, so you'll have to talk to Watkins.
什么另一个人
What other guy?
他到底在这里干什么
What the hell is he doing here?
-你跟他说什么了  -什么都没说
- What did you tell him? - Nothing.
贝克特  我知道他是你在纽约的搭档...
Beckett, I know he was your partner in New York--
不不  我发誓  我什么都没跟他说
No, no, I swear. I didn't say anything to him.
那他为什么在这里
Then why is he here?
贝克特探员
Agent Beckett.
麦考德探员
Agent McCord.
-你们在这里做什么  -你在这里做什么
- What are you guys doing here? - What are you doing here?
我是这么想的  既然贝克特要工作  我...
Well, I figured since, uh, beckett was working, I'd--
我就在这儿打几个球
I'd just get in a few rounds.
那你的球棍呢
Where are your clubs?
糟糕
Crap.
你知道如果我告诉长官
Do you realize what would happen
他在这里会有什么后果吗
if I told the chief that he was here?
你会被逐出团队
You would be kicked off the team,
更别说你还会面临妨碍公务罪的起诉
not to mention obstruction charges against you.
我就警告你这一次
This is my one and only warning.
下次再让我看到你  最好是在书壳上
The next time I see you, it'd better be on a book jacket.
好吧  别邀请她参加婚礼
Okay, she is not invited to the wedding.
"来打几个球"
"Get in a few rounds"?
你要我说什么  说你不小心把
What did you want me to say, that you accidentally left out
炸毁的变压器证物照落在家了吗
your evidence photo of the blown transformer?
卡塞尔  你居然看了我的机密证物照
Castle, you went through my classified photos?
-你到底在做什么  -想帮你
- What the hell were you doing? - Trying to help.
-我也没想到会被抓住  -是啊  逮个正着
- I didn't think I'd get caught. - Yeah, well, you did.
-是啊  -不过你是怎么来的
- Yeah. - How'd you get here, anyway?
我是说你为什么会来这里
I mean, why are you here?
那个变压器把我引到一个研究园区
Well, the transformer led me to a research park
那里的所有的租户都是政府承包商
where all the tenants have government contracts.
我猜他们可能是利用断电
I figured maybe they're using the blackout
来避开安保系统
to circumvent the security system.
但他们也不能大摇大摆地从正门进出
But they're not just gonna waltz in through the front door.
然后我就想起我们之前的案子
Then I remembered that case we had at the old haunt,
-凶手利用了...  -利用了纽约地下
- where the killer used-- - Used the abandoned sewer tunnels
废弃的下水管道  没错
underneath New York. Yes.
你也想到了
You thought of it, too.
但是  这里不是纽约
Except... this isn't New York.
你知道看一眼那张照片
Do you realize how many laws were broken
你要触犯多少条法律吗
by looking at that photo?
你是想害我被开除吗
Are you trying to get me fired?
这样会让我见你容易些
Would make it easier to see you.
要是我进监狱了也没用
Not if I was in jail.
也是
Right.
听着  我也想见你
Look, I wanna see you, too,
但我们不能这样  好吗
But it can't be like this, okay?
你得保证停止妨碍调查
You have to promise you're gonna stop fiddling with this investigation.
行  我保证
Okay. Yeah. I promise.
但你能不能至少听一听我的发现呢
But wouldn't you at least like to hear what I found out?
好吧
Right.
断电那晚  这些人什么都没有看见
These guys didn't see anything the night of the blackout.
因为太黑
It was too dark.
但那个保安
But that guard over there
记得在几天前见过一个人
remembers seeing a guy a couple days ago
开着一辆90年代末款的金色轿车
in a late '90s model gold sedan.
-他很可能是在做某种调查  -卡塞尔
- He's probably doing some kind of recon. - Castle--
-如果你让他们把监控录像送来...  -卡塞尔
- If you have them send over their surveillance footage-- - Castle.
卡塞尔  拜托
Castle! Please.
好吧
Right.
抱歉  好了  我退出  我不...  我保证
Sorry. Okay. I'm out. I-I-I didn't--I promise.
记忆清空
Wiped from my brain.
就像我从没来过
Like I wasn't even here.
-我得走了  -当然
- I gotta go. - Of course.
能想到排水管非常好
Nice job with the drainage tunnel.
继续努力  贝克特
Keep up the good work, Beckett.
谢谢你
Thank you...
没提卡塞尔的事
For, uh, not saying anything about Castle.
听着
Look...
我刚毕业的第一年
When I was a year out of Quantico,
我一心扑在案子上
I was busting my ass on this case--
我的第一个好机会
my first big chance,
我们跟了那个案子长达一个月
and we'd been going at it straight for a month,
我特别想释放些压力
and I really wanted to let off some steam,
于是我去了家酒吧  随便找了个男人
so I went to a bar, and I picked up a guy,
就把他带回了家
and I took him home.
第二天一早  他问我  斯科菲尔德是谁
Next morning, he says, "Who's Scofield?"
斯科菲尔德是我们这次高度机密调查的主角
Scofield was the subject of our highly classified investigation.
你睡觉的时候说了
You talked in your sleep?
这工作就这样  什么都可能发生
It's this job. Things happen.
你得确保下不为例
You better make sure they only happen once.
高尔夫球场的监控录像来了
Golf course security video's in.
这是高尔夫球场入口的街对面
This is across the street from the entrance to the golf course
前天的监控录像
the day before yesterday.
据说车停靠了十五分钟
Our guy said the car stayed like this for 15 minutes.
车牌看得清吗
Can we get a plate?
角度不好  看不清
Ah, the angle's just not good enough.
驾车人呢
What about the driver?
很清晰
Pretty clear shot.
正在生成特征向量图像以进行面部识别
Creating a feature vector descriptor to run facial recognition.
先从军方数据库里查
Check the military databases first.
这人受过训练
This guy's had training.
这是两天前
This was two days ago.
闯入的前一天
That's the day before the break-in.
他在计划逃脱路线
He's planning his escape route.
找到匹配的了
We've got a match.
驾车人叫杰克·布朗森  35岁
Driver was Jack Bronson, 35.
刚从海军陆战队侦察队退役
Recently retired marine force recon.
最后一次轮岗是做秘密谍报
His last rotation he worked black ops,
专长于前沿渗透
specializing in forward position infiltration.
查得到他的住址吗
You got an address on this guy?
安全
Clear!
Clear.
他不在
He's not here.
但留下了这个
Except he left this.
作案工具
Tools of the trade.
C-4炸药用来炸变压器
C-4 to blow up the transformer.
剪线钳用来切断备用发电机电线
Wire cutters to disable the backup generator rope
滑轮用于通风井
and pulleys for the air shaft.
这就是我们要找的人
This is our guy.
好好搜一遍
Tear this place apart.
加密系统不在这里
We're not gonna find that encryption system here.
那是他的筹码
That's his meal ticket.
无论去哪他都会带在身边
Wherever he went, that thing's going with him.
亨德里克斯  联系局里  调他的通话记录
Hendricks, call the office. Pull his phone records.
信用卡记录  我要知道他联系过谁
Run his credit cards. I wanna know who he talks to,
在哪吃东西  去哪个健身房
where he eats, what gym he goes to.
同时查查他的女友
And have him look for a girlfriend.
如果他要跑路  也许有个帮手
If he's on the run, he might have help.
卡塞尔  有什么事吗
Hey, Castle, everything okay?
红的还是白的
Red or white?
什么
What?
你想要什么酒配三文鱼
What kind of wine do you want with your salmon?
我在准备晚餐
I'm cooking you dinner tonight
作为给你惹麻烦的补偿
to make up for getting you in trouble at work.
太贴心了
That's so sweet.
我知道
Yeah, I know. Um...
-案子怎么样了  -卡塞尔
- So how's the case going? - Castle.
不  我只是想知道应该几时开始做饭
No, I just wanna know when to start cooking.
相信我  我明白的  静音区
Trust me. I got the message. Cone of silence.
教会与国家  互不干涉
Church and state. No more interference.
好吧  既然那样的话  红酒
Okay, well, then in that case, red, and, um...
你能弄到那种让我那啥的吗
can you get that kind that makes me feel all...
我会买一箱的  晚上见
I'll buy a whole case. See you tonight.
我们一起走到我的车边上
We're gonna walk over to my car together,
你坐进去  装作认识我的样子
and you're gonna get in like you know me.
但我不认识你啊
Yeah, but I don't know you,
我手头还有三文鱼要赶紧冷藏
and I have salmon here that needs to be refrigerated.
好吧  好吧
Okay. Okay.
这是...90年代末产的金色轿车
Hey, this is a... late '90s gold sedan.
你是那个...
You're the guy--
好吧  听着
Okay, look,
你搞错了吧
you're making a mistake here, okay?
我不...不  红灯啊亲
I don't--I don't-- that's a red. That's a red.
天呐  停车
Hey, god! God! Stop!
天呐
Jeez!
我不知道你以为我是谁
I don't know who you think I am.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你在高尔夫球场跟调查局的人在一起
You were at the golf course with the feds.
她们掌握了些什么
What do they know?
我...我不知道
I-I-I'm not sure.
他们在监视我吗
Are they looking at me?
-他们知道瓦尔基里吗  -我不知道
- Do they know about Valkyrie? - I don't know! I don't know!
我发誓  我甚至都不该来在这
All right? I swear. I-I wasn't even supposed to be there.
他们...有没有谈到过瓦尔基里
Did they... say anything about Valkyrie?
兄弟你没事吧
Hey, man, are you okay?
坚...持...不...住...了
Mnh-mnh. Can't... Hold... On.
去...梦乡
Going... To dream... World.
手把在方向盘十点和两点方向
Hands at 10 and 2.
振作起来  伙计
Come on, buddy.
往左拐
Heading on the left.
布朗森
Bronson?
是他
That's him.
-硬件模块呢  -不在车里
- What about the hardware module? - It's not in the car.
-有人跟他同车吗  -有
- Anybody riding with him? - Yep.
-女友  -不
- Girlfriend? - Nope.
他
That guy.
开玩笑呢吧
You've gotta be kidding me.
我来处理
You know what? I'll--I'll deal with him.
不  你没机会了
No. You've already had your chance.
亨德里克斯  请逮捕卡塞尔先生
Hendricks, please place Mr. Castle under arrest.
有人吗
Hello?
有人在吗
Is anyone even there?
贝克特在哪  让我跟她说
Where's Beckett? Let me talk to her.
恐怕她帮不了你
I'm afraid she can't help you.
听着  这都是误会
Look, this has just been a misunderstanding.
你跟一个我们认为是美国公敌的人
You were in a car with a man who we believe
坐在同一辆车里
is an enemy combatant of the United States.
这可不是什么误会  卡塞尔先生
That's not a misunderstanding, Mr. Castle.
这触犯了联邦法律
That's a federal offense.
我被他用枪胁迫
I was abducted at gunpoint.
是吗  世上这么多人
Is that so? And of all the people in the world,
为什么我们的嫌疑犯偏偏绑架了你呢
why would our chief suspect abduct you?
我不知道  他说他在高尔夫球场看到我
I don't know. He said he saw me at the golf course
跟贝克特和麦考德在一起
with Beckett and McCord.
你为什么恰好在高尔夫球场
Why exactly were you at the golf course?
你为什么在华盛顿  卡塞尔先生
Why are you in D.C., Mr. Castle?
我来这里见未婚妻
I'm here to see my fiancee.
但你为什么
But why did you choose
选在这周来见她呢
to see her on this particular weekend?
我...
Well, I...
等等
Oh, now wait a minute.
你不会以为我跟这案子有关吧
What, you don't think I'm involved in this, do you?
听着
Okay, look...
那个男的在街上向我走来
A man walked up to me on the street,
用枪指着我  逼我坐进一辆车
shoved a gun in my ribs and forced me into a car.
之后他就开始审问我
Then he started questioning me,
你们知不知道他或是瓦尔基里
whether or not you guys know about him or about Valkyrie.
-瓦尔基里  -对
-Valkyrie? -Yeah.
什么是瓦尔基里
What's Valkyrie?
我也不知道
I don't know!
我告诉他我不知道
I told him I didn't know,
然后他就死了  就在车里
and then he dropped dead right in the car.
莫名其妙  而你就坐在他旁边
Mysteriously? With you sitting next to him.
没有  我们的数据库里
No, there's nothing relevant about Valkyrie
没有和瓦尔基里相关的信息
in any of our databases.
可能是布朗森的联系人或者买家
It could be the name of Bronson's contact or buyer.
他们发现我们查到他  就除掉了他
They must have found out we were on to him and taken him out.
这就意味着加密系统下落不明
Which means the encryption system's in play.
长官  我知道这看起来有蹊跷
Sir, I know what this looks like,
但是我发誓卡塞尔和这事无关
but I swear to you, Castle's not involved in any of this.
我们知道
We know he isn't.
我们有自动提款机录像证明他是被劫持的
We have A.T.M. footage on him being abducted at gunpoint,
正如你所说
just like you said.
那你为什么
Well, then why did you--
我要确保他把知道的都告诉我们
I needed to make sure he told us everything he knew,
考虑到你未婚未的"光辉历史"
and given your fiance's history,
他需要彻底地明白
he needed to learn once and for all
不要去搀和联邦案件
to keep his nose out of federal business.
布朗森的死因有消息了么
Any word yet on how Bronson died?
他们正在做尸检
They're doing the autopsy right now.
长官  我们有发现
Sir, we've got something.
-卡塞尔怎么办  -让他再担心受怕一会儿
-Uh, what about Castle? -Let him sweat.
对不住了
I'm sorry.
这是珍奈特·米勒 布朗森的女友
So this is Jeanette Miller, Bronson's girlfriend
极有可能是他的同伙
and most likely his accomplice.
他们交往了六个月
Uh, they've been dating for six months.
电话记录显示布朗森在劫持卡塞尔先生之前
Phone records show that bronson called her
给她打了好几次电话
a number of times right before he abducted Mr. Castle,
而且她曾是谢尔顿议员的助手
and get this--she worked as an aide to Senator Shelton.
谢尔顿是外交关系委员会的高官
Shelton's a ranking member of the foreign relations committee.
她有能帮助布朗森
She'd have the connections to help Bronson
将加密系统转移出国的通道
move the encryption system out of the country.
她参与了这件事  找到她就找到了系统
She's part of this. Find her, you find that system.
知道她在哪吗
You have a location on her?
我们追踪了她的手机GPS
We tracked the G.P.S. on her phone
位于罗斯蒙特的一条街上
to a street in Rosemont,
但当我们几分钟前行动时
But when we moved in a few minutes ago,
只发现了手机和车  都被丢弃了
we found the phone and her car, both abandoned.
她销声匿迹了
She's off the grid.
她知道我们在找她
She knows we're looking for her.
我要你们监视这个城市的每个角落
I want every inch of this city under surveillance.
获取每条街道
You tap into every sidewalk,
交通和公共交通的监视录像
traffic and mass transit video feed.
用人脸识别系统以70%的匹配率查所有图像
Run everything through facial recognition with a 70% match.
她可能更改了她的外貌
She may have altered her appearance.
我要找到她
I want her found.
明白  长官
You got it, Sir.
等等  贝克特
Not you, Beckett.
我有事要找你谈
You and I have something else to discuss.
告诉我这有比咖啡更有劲的东西
Please tell me there's something stronger than coffee in there.
抱歉了
Sorry.
我到底闯了多大的祸
So... How much trouble am I in?
没我闯的大
Not as much as me.
听着  卡塞尔
Look, Castle...
我无法让一切回到从前  是不是
I can't make it like it was before, can I?
或许比以前更好呢
Maybe it'll be better.
这样一来  我们晚上回到家
This way, when we come home at the end of each day,
就有的聊了
we'll have something to talk about,
像普通的情侣一样
like normal couples.
只是你的日常工作是保密的
Only your day will be classified.
我们会找到平衡点的
We're gonna make this work.
我保证
I promise.
这案子结了  我有几天假
I'll have a couple of days off after this case,
我们会找出法子的  但在这之前
and--and we'll figure it out, but until then--
你不用说了
You don't have to say it.
我乘早上第一班飞机走
I'll be on the first flight out in the morning.
C先生
Mr. C.!
肿么啦
Que pasa?
派
Pi.
阿丽克西斯去哪了
Where's Alexis?
她和奶奶去逛街了
She went shopping with her grandma.
我主动请缨做晚饭
I volunteered to make dinner tonight,
刚刚开始准备
and I'm just getting a jump on the prep.
你要吃美味多汁牛排吗
Can I count you in on a nice, juicy steak?
这不是牛排
These aren't steaks.
这是木瓜牛排
That's papaya steak.
最多汁的牛排
It's the juiciest steak there is.
这都是水果
This is all fruit.
我是果食主义者
I'm a fruitarian.
那是必须的
Course you are.
我只吃水果
It's all that I eat.
人类最原始的饮食
Original diet of mankind.
天赐的营养
Nutrition as god intended.
你知道吗  派  别多想  但是
You know, Pi, don't, uh, take this the wrong way, but...
你打算在我家待多久
How long do you plan on staying at casa de Castle?
我现在有点麻烦
You know, I'm actually in a little bit of a bind.
我住在阿姆斯特丹
See, I live in Amsterdam,
但我把护照丢了
but I, uh... kinda lost my passport.
哎呀  别再为我的烦心事操心了
But, hey, you don't wanna hear about my troubles.
你也麻烦多多啊
You got your own, right?
是啊
I do now.
你打算清理干净吗
You are gonna clean all this up?
C先生
Mr. C.,
我能感觉到你和未婚妻
I get the feeling things didn't go too well
在华盛顿不太顺利
in D.C. with your fiancee, did they?
是的  派
No, Pi. They did not.
有的时候  最好的方法
You know, sometimes the best thing to do...
就是谈谈
is talk about it.
你说得太对了
You know what? You're absolutely right.
你去哪
Where you goin'?
我得找个人谈谈
I'm going to find someone to talk about it with.
找到布朗森女友了吗
Any luck tracking down Bronson's girlfriend?
还没
Not yet.
卡塞尔安全到家了
Castle get home okay?
是  挺好的
Yeah. Fine.
你想聊聊吗
You wanna talk about it?
不想
No.
很好
Good.
找到了吗
You get a hit?
不是完全匹配
Possible match. Uh...
-87%的可能性  -放大看看
- 87% certainty? - Bring it up.
这是交通摄像头的实时监控录像
This is traffic cam video, streaming live.
她染了头发  不过应该就是她
Well, she dyed her hair, but that's her.
她肩上背的包
And that bag on her shoulder...
你认为里面装的是加密系统
You think she's got the encryption system in it?
查查就知道了
Let's go find out.
等会  她出画面了
Wait. We're losing her.
转换摄像头
Switching feeds.
有了
There.
这是哪
Where is this?
20街和P接岔口  杜邦圈附近
20th and P, near Dupont Circle.
我是麦考德  我们要追踪杜邦圈附近的一个目标
This is McCord. We need to acquire a target near Dupont Circle.
又出画面了
We're losing her again.
-她不见了  -里奇蒙德
- She's gone. - Richmond.
她肯定是躲进了某家商店或是巷子里
She must have ducked into a store or alley.
或是地铁  该死的  随时待命
Or the metro. Damn it. Stand by.
你能不能给我看一下她刚才走的路线
Can you just display the route that she was following?
好的  正在分析她的路径
Okay. It's analyzing her path.
她并没有选择最直接的路径
It doesn't look like she's taking a direct route.
她更像是在用躲避策略
It's like she's using evasive tactics.
如果她是从罗斯蒙特出发的话
Okay, so if she started off in Rosemont...
她行进的大致轨迹是朝着
her general trajectory leads to...
联合车站
Union Station.
她要逃跑
She's making a run for it.
自从我和珍妮认识  我们俩分开的时间
You know, I don't think Jenny and I have been apart
就从来没有超过两天
for more than two days since we met.
你俩现在这样肯定很难熬
It's gotta be rough.
我只是觉得我们都不同步了
I just feel like we're so far out of synch.
我不知道怎么才能回到之前的状态
I don't know how to get back.
我想我可能只是想找回原来的感觉
Guess I was just...trying to make it feel like us again.
是啊  包括拿我和莱恩当猴耍
Yeah, by playing me and Ryan for chumps.
你应该知道我们早晚会发现
You should have known that we were gonna
这个案子是真的
figure out this case was real.
因果报应
Well, you'll be happy to know that for my sins,
我被一个疯子拿枪劫持  还差点死掉
I was abducted by a maniac at gunpoint and nearly killed,
不过至少我没害得贝克特被炒鱿鱼
but at least I didn't get Beckett fired.
什么  劫持
Whoa, whoa. Abducted?
被谁
By who?
兄弟们  我真不能跟你们讨论这事
Look, guys, I really shouldn't be talking about this.
拜托  卡塞尔  咱们谁跟谁呀
Come on, Castle. It's us.
而且拜你所赐
And thanks to you,
我们已经身陷其中了
we're already involved.
好吧  但这事不能再牵扯别人了  明白吗
Okay, but this goes no further, all right?
我在街上走
So I'm just walking down the street,
突然间  他们要找的这个人
and this guy that they're looking for
冲出来抓住我  把我塞进车里
grabs me, shoves me into a car,
然后就开始胡言乱语  问我一堆问题
starts talking crazy, asking all these questions.
-什么问题  -什么什么瓦尔基里之类的
- What kind of questions? - Something about Valkyrie,
之后我以为他要晕倒
and then I thought he was gonna pass out
因为他一直说什么要去梦乡
because he was talking about going off to dream world.
但结果他没晕倒
But he didn't pass out.
他死了
He dropped dead.
这个家伙  他
Uh, this guy -- was he, uh...
他是军人吗
was he military?
怎么了  瓦尔基里是军事用语吗
Why, is "Valkyrie" a military term?
我不知道瓦尔基里是不是
I don't know about "Valkyrie",
但是"梦乡"
but "dream world" --
是位于波斯湾的高度机密特别行动基地
it's a highly classified special operations base in the gulf.
那是个幽灵基地
It's a ghost base.
政府从来不承认它的存在
The government's never confirmed its existence,
但是我
but I...
我认识一个人  他的一个朋友驻扎在那里
I met a guy who knew a guy who was stationed there.
基地在哪
Where is it?
我都说那是个幽灵基地了  卡塞尔
I-it--it's a ghost base, Castle.
你认为他会告诉我具体位置吗
You think he's gonna say where it is?
当然不会  但我可以告诉你
No. But I will tell you this.
如果贝克特的案子跟这个基地有联系
If Beckett's case has anything to do with this base,
那她要对付的问题可比她想象的要大得多
Well, then she's into something way bigger than she realizes.
在那
There.
目标正前往夹层楼面  准备逮捕
Target is moving to the mezzanine. Close in.
-不  等一下  别着急  -待命
- No, wait. Not yet. - Stand by.
你想让她上火车吗
Would you like her to catch a train?
我觉得不对劲
No, something else is going on.
她把她的车丢在了罗斯蒙特
She abandoned her car in Rosemont,
然后大老远地跑到这里来
and then she came all the way out here?
也许她以为自己被人跟踪了
Maybe she thought she was being followed.
那她为什么不在亚历山德里亚上火车呢
Then why didn't she just hop the train in Alexandria?
也许她想坐的那条线从这里发车呢
Maybe the line she wants only leaves from here.
又或者她是要来这里见她的买家
Or maybe she's meeting her buyer here.
是你教我要跟随自己的直觉的
You're the one that told me to follow my instincts,
我的直觉告诉我  我们应该等
and my instincts say that we should wait.
联合车站全楼禁烟
Union Station is a nonsmoking building...
我给你的直觉两分钟
I'll give your instincts two minutes.
原地待命
Hold position.
她人呢  她跑哪去了
Where is she? Where did she go?
我就知道我们不该等
I knew it. I knew we shouldn't have done this.
不  她在储物柜那边
No, by the lockers.
珍奈特·米勒  我们是联邦探员  你被捕了
Jeanette Miller. Federal agents. You're under arrest.
-什么  -不要引起骚动
- What? - Let's do this quietly.
-站到一边去  -什么  我干什么了
- Step away. - What? What did I do?
我已经告诉过你们了
Look, I told you,
我这辈子就没见过这个东西
I have never seen this before in my life.
那它怎么会在那个储物柜里呢
Then what was it doing in that locker?
走私政府财产
Trafficking government property,
妨碍国家安全  叛国
jeopardizing national security, treason --
每一项罪名都够判你终身监禁的了
each one is punishable by life imprisonment.
或是死刑  你的计划到底是什么
Or worse. What was the plan, anyway?
有人雇你和杰克·布朗森去偷的吗
Did someone hire you and Jack Bronson to steal it?
你们不明白  事情没有这么简单
You don't understand. This isn't how it looks.
是吗  你可是扔了你的手机
Really? Because you dumped your phone,
弃了你的车  还染了头发
and then you dumped your car and you dyed your hair.
很显然你想要人间蒸发
Clearly you're trying to disappear.
因为杰克惹上麻烦了  他被人陷害了  我也是
Because Jack was in trouble. He's being set up. We both are.
-珍奈特  -听我说
- Jeanette -- - Listen.
他两天前的夜里接到了一个电话
He got a call a couple of nights ago --
有人约他在高尔夫球场见面
someone wanting to meet him at a golf course.
我不知道他们说了什么  但杰克吓坏了
And whatever they said freaked Jack out,
于是他就去了  但是约他的人一直没有出现
so he went out there, but the guy never showed.
当他听说入室盗窃案后
And then when he heard about the break-in,
他意识到他们给他设了套
he realized they'd set him up.
-谁  -他不知道
- Who? - He didn't know.
但杰克很害怕  他从未这样过
But Jack was scared, and Jack does not get scared.
他说我们得跑路
And he said that we needed to go on the run
直到他弄清发生了什么
until he could figure out what was going on.
他让我去找他在联合车站的储物柜
And he told me to go to his locker at Union Station,
里面放着钱
that there'd be money there...
他会尽快和我见面
and he'd meet up with me when he could.
如果他没参与
Okay, if he wasn't involved,
那模块是怎么出现在他储物柜的
then how did that end up in his locker?
我不知道  也许是陷害的一部分
I don't know. Maybe it's part of the setup.
瓦尔基里是什么
What's Valkyrie?
-瓦尔基里  -关于瓦尔基里  杰克跟你说了什么
- Valkyrie? - What did Jack tell you about Valkyrie?
杰克在哪儿  你知道他在哪吗
Look, where is Jack? Do you know where he is?
不
Oh, no.
她有加密系统
She had the encryption system.
还有海外关系网
she had the overseas contacts,
她干了这么多事
and yet after everything she did,
还指望我们相信她是无辜的吗
she really expects us to believe she wasn't involved?
为了爱  人会干疯狂的事
Well, people do crazy things when they're in love.
我注意到了
I noticed.
别告诉我你相信她
Don't tell me you believe her.
她说得对  布朗森是被陷害的
Well, she's right. Bronson was being set up.
-你为什么这么想  -他公寓里的工具
- And why do you think that? - The tools in his apartment,
高尔夫球场的监控录像
the security footage from the golf course,
甚至他储物柜里的加密系统
even the encryption system in his locker--
像他这种受过训练的人不会如此低级
someone with his training wouldn't be that sloppy.
你觉得这份工作最难的地方是什么吗
You know what the hardest thing about this job is?
-什么  -知道什么叫适可而止
- What? - Knowing when to stop doing this job.
我们拿到了加密系统
We have the encryption system.
抓到了坏人  这就是胜利
We got the bad guy. This is a victory.
在火车站我没错
I wasn't wrong in the train station,
现在我也没错
and I'm not wrong here.
还有我们忽略的地方
There is something that we're missing.
好吧
Okay.
就算有人陷害了布朗森
Let's just say someone did have it out for Bronson.
他们为什么费这么大力气
Why would they go through all the effort
精心策划了一场停电
to orchestrate a blackout,
入侵政府秘密工厂
break into a secure government facility,
只为偷一个我们注定会追回的东西
only to steal something that they knew we'd recover?
陷害一个人用不着这么麻烦
There are many easier ways to set someone up.
等等  你说得对
Wait. I mean, you're right.
为什么要费这么大劲
Why would someone go through all the trouble
去偷一个我们注定能追回的东西
to steal something just so that we would recover it?
除非是为了转移我们的注意
Unless it was a diversion.
如果说他们要找的
What if it wasn't the encryption system
不是机密系统呢
that they were really after?
他们只想让我们认为这是他们想要的
They just wanted us to think that that's what they were after.
他们既然能从通风井进入赛博科技
And the air shaft that they used to access Cybertech--
他们就能进入同一栋楼的
they could have used that to access any of the floors
任何楼层
in that same building.
赛博科技是在三层和四层
Cybertech is on floors 3 and 4.
是的
Right, and...
五层和六层是一个基因实验室
5 and 6 are a genetics lab.
七层是一家咨询公司
7... is a consulting firm.
八层
and 8...
没有八层租户的详细信息
There are no details about the tenant on 8.
显示为机密
It says it's classified.
八层有什么
What's on 8?
梦乡秘密基地
搜索无结果
你要来吗  爸爸
Are you coming, dad?
晚饭好了
Dinner's ready.
是的  我得快点
Oh, yes. I'd best hurry.
我可不想让我的木瓜牛排变冷
I wouldn't want my papaya steak to get cold.
你吃过了吗  它们很好吃
Have you even tried them? They're delicious.
你们先吃吧
Maybe you should start without me.
我现在有点忙
I'm right in the middle of something.
你不是在躲避派吧
You're not avoiding Pi, are you?
不  宝贝  我在为故事做些研究
No, sweetheart. I'm just doing some research for a story.
你确定你没在调查贝克特的案子吗
You sure you're not still looking into Beckett's case?
你可是保证不搅和的哦
Even after you promised not to?
我来开门
I'll get it.
没事的
Look, it's fine.
没人会知道的
No one's ever gonna know.
理查德  这些人是找你的
Richard, these men are here for you.
他们是联调局探员
They say they're Federal Agents.
-卡塞尔  你得跟我们走一趟  -什么事
- Castle, you need to come with us right away. - What is this about?
-先生  请跟我们走一趟  -为什么
- Please, sir, just come with us. - Why?
等等  你们不能就这样把他带走
Hold on. We-- well, wait a minute. You can't just take him away.
-帮我个忙  给我律师打电话  -好的
- Do me a favor. Um, call up my lawyer. - Okay.
-爸爸  -给贝克特打电话
- Dad? - And--and call Beckett.
好
Okay.
我的天呐
Oh, my god.
贝克特  你终于来了
Beckett. Finally.
发生什么了  为什么没人跟我说
What's going on? Why won't anyone talk to me?
他们为什么要抽我的血
And why would they take my blood?
卡塞尔  你知道我调查的那个案子
Castle, you know that case that I've been investigating?
入室盗窃案
The, um, the break-in and the theft?
其实它另有隐情
Well, it turns out there's more to it than we thought.
你是打算对我用水刑吗
Are you gonna waterboard me?
那会严重影响我们之间的感情
Because that would seriously affect our relationship.
不  亲爱的  你听我说
No, babe, can-- can you listen for a second?
我们发现同一栋楼的另一家实验室
It turns out that something else was stolen from another lab
丢了别的东西
in that building.
是他们为军队研发的
It was a chemical agent that they were working on
一种化学试剂  被认为太危险不能投产
for the military, but it was deemed to dangerous to use.
丢失的计量足以杀死几千人
The amount stolen was enough to kill thousands of people.
这种事情应该不用告诉我吧
Isn't this "need-to-know" stuff?
你为什么要告诉我
Why are you telling me?
因为这种毒剂杀死了杰克·布朗森
Because that toxin was used to kill Jack Bronson,
那个劫持你的人
the man that abducted you.
毒剂是雾化状态的
It was aerosolized.
它被放置在他汽车的通风装置中
It was placed in the ventilation system of his car.
我在那辆车里待过
I was in that car.
我是不是
Was I...
有多严重
How bad?
根据它在你血液中的含量
Based on the amount found in your bloodstream,
你只剩不到一天的生命
you have less than a day to live.